{
    "id": "7b325209c1e54e159c377c255671366f",
    "title": "As, Since, Because, Owing To, Due To, So",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We stayed inside ……………. it was raining.",
            "description": "Because of and owing to are prepositions. They are followed by nouns. Because is a conjunction. It is followed by a clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "because of",
                "owing to",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b4cbe87c81cb4f26bbbce4ea67387e6c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wanted to leave early ……………. I was not enjoying the party.",
            "description": "The conjunctions as, since and because can all be used to refer to the reason for something. ",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "as",
                "because",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "b34445be5f0e46e3abe5b598876031c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl stayed at home ……………… her illness.",
            "description": "Due to and owing to are interchangeable. Both of them are prepositions and are followed by nouns. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "due to",
                "owing to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "249e1c60cd014015bd38ea357d0f8800"
        },
        {
            "question": "We were late ……………. the traffic jam.",
            "description": "As, since and because are conjunctions. They are followed by clauses. Because of is a preposition. It is followed by a noun. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "because of",
                "as",
                "since"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bb818a6fb0094248a385f76bec84716d"
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t love cats ………………. she wasn’t happy when her husband bought two kittens home.",
            "description": "The conjunctions as, since and because introduce the reason so introduces the result. ",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "so",
                "since",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "59fe1b60645543328e8daf7a598f2785"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ravi didn’t play …………….. his illness.",
            "description": "Due to and owing to both mean because of.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "owing to",
                "due to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8f38591c591a47909f05244abbe94d5d"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………. I was tired, I went to bed early.",
            "description": "The conjunction as introduces the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "So",
                "Because of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ab2ec08af9ad4b91a558572615f4025f"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was very unhappy ……………. she missed her children.",
            "description": "The conjunctions for and because have very similar meanings. For is common in a formal written style. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "so",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4ca97f75f4424d6eaa0488b3918c7364"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………. bad weather, we cancelled the trip.",
            "description": "All of the given options are possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "Due to",
                "Owing to",
                "Because of"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3d580d12282f4ca795bdd12cf797b2c6"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………… I was having a nice time, I decided to stay longer.",
            "description": "We use the conjunction 'as' to show the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "So",
                "Because of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6778a82ee7f14b95bb6245d647ebdc53"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………. it was very cold, he put on his coat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "So",
                "Because of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "81c3a54cf0144d058142dcfd44b6656f"
        },
        {
            "question": "She couldn’t walk ……………. she had broken her leg.",
            "description": "Because of, due to and owing to are prepositions. They cannot be followed by a clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "because of",
                "due to",
                "owing to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "63f626858a2f4d5785751ef91515ba78"
        }
    ]
}